Erwin Chargaff Papers 1929-1992 Mss.B.C37
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Works by Chargaff, 1929-1989; 15.5 linear feet
  - Synthesis of a Radioactive Organic Compound: Alpha-Glycerophosphoric Acid, [1938]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 100)
  - Synthesis of Novel Ribonucleic Acids and Proteins During Chloroplast Formation in Resting Euglena Cells, 5/14; Chargaff, George Brawerman and Carole Ann Rebman (Box 100)
  - Synthesis of Ribonucleic Acids in the Adrenal Cortex: Early Effects of Adrenocorticotropic Hormone, 5/17; Chargaff and Edwin D. Bransome, Jr. (Box 100)
  - Techniques for the Demonstration by Chromatography of Nitrogenous Lipide Constituents, Sulfur-Containing Amino Acids, and Reducing Sugars, [1948]; Chargaff, Celia Levine and Charlotte Green (Box 100)
  - Template Functions in the Enzymic Formation of Polyribonucleotides, I. Integrity of the DNA Template, [1966]; Chargaff and John D. Karkas (Box 100)
    Manuscript
  - Template Functions in the Enzymic Formation of Polyribonucleotides, I. Integrity of the DNA Template, [1966]; Chargaff and John D. Karkas (Box 100)
  - Template Functions in the Enzymic Formation of Polyribonucleotides, II. Metaphase Chromosomes as Templates in the Enzymic Synthesis of Ribonucleic Acids, [1966]; Chargaff, John D. Karkas and Hans Türler (Box 100)
  - Template Functions in the Enzymic Formation of Polyribonucleotides, III. Apurinic Acid as Template, [1966]; Chargaff and John D. Karkas (Box 100)
    See also Ser.VI, Template Functions in the Enzymic
  - Template Functions in the Enzymic Formation of Polyribonucleotides, IV. Denatured DNA as Template, [1967]; Chargaff and John D. Karkas (Box 101)
  - Template Properties of Complementary Fractions of Denatured Microbial Deoxyribonucleic Acids, [1970]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - The Thromboplastic Activity of Tissue Phosphatides, [1944]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - The Thromboplastic Protein: Structure, Properties, Disintegration, [1944]; Chargaff, Aaron Bendich and Seymour S. Cohen (Box 101)
  - Transferase from Escherichia Coli Effecting Low-Energy Phosphate Transfer to Nucleosides and Nucleotides, [1970]; Chargaff and Elinor F. Brunngraber (Box 101)
  - Translational Complementarity of RNA Transcripts of Native and Denatured B. Subtilis DNA, [1970]; Chargaff and Era Cassuto (Box 101)
  - Triviality in Science: A Brief Meditation on Fashions, [1976]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Type of Attachment of Sialic Acid in Ox-Brain Mucolipid, 5/13; Chargaff and Abraham Rosenberg (Box 101)
  - Ueber das Fett der Tuberkelbakterien, [193-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Über das Fett und das Phosphatid der Diphtheriebakterien, [1933]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Über das Vorkommen Einer Ungesättigten Hexakosansäure im Fett der Tuberkelbakterien, [1930]; Chargaff and R.J. Anderson (Box 101)
  - Über den Gegenwärtigen Stand der Chemischen Erforschung des Tuberkelbazillus, [1931]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Über den Lipoidgehalt Verschiedener Typen von Tuberkelbazillen, [1932]; Chargaff and Joseph Dieryck (Box 101)
  - Ueber die Carotinoiden Pigmente Zweier Säurefester Bakterien, [193-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Über die Charakterisierung von Fetten in Geringen Substanzmengen, [1931]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Ueber die Chemie Pathogener Bakterien, 4/14; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Ueber die Chemie Pathogener Bakterien, Mit Esonderer Berücksichtigung der Lipoidsubstanzen, 18 Dec. 1931; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Ueber die Chemie der Diphtheriebakterien und Anderer Pathogener Mikroorganismen, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
    See Ser.III, Zur Chemie der Diphtheriebakterien und
  - Über die Katalytische Zersetzung Einiger Jodverbindungen, 4/12; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Über die Lipoide des Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG), [1933]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Über die Zusammensetzung des Gesamten Extrahierbaren Fettes der Tuberkelbakterien, [1930]; Chargaff and R.J. Anderson (Box 101)
  - Über Höhere Fettsäuren Mit Verzweigter Kohlenstoffkette, [1932]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 101)
  - Ultracentrifugal Isolation from Lung Tissue of a Macromolecular Protein Component with Thromboplastic Properties, [1942]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Uneven Distribution of 5-Methylcytosine in Fractions of Wheat Germ Deoxyribonucleic Acid, [1955]; Chargaff and Rakoma Lipshitz-Weisner (Box 102)
  - Unidentified, 6/10; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Unidentified, n.d.; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Unstable Isotopes. I. The Determination of Radioactive Isotopes in Organic Material, [1939]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Unstable Isotopes. II. The Relative Speed of Formation of Lecithin and Cephalin in the Body, [1939]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Unstable Isotopes. III. Synthesis of Radioactive a-Glycerophosphoric Acid, [1939?]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Untersuchungen Über die Pipoidverteilung in Verschiedenen Tuberkelbazillenstämmen, [193-]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - An Unwritten Letter to the Director of the National Institutes of Health, 5/3; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Venerable Nuisances: On Cultural Criticism and Cultural Conservatism, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - The Very Big and the Very Small - Remarks on Conjugated Proteins, 5/8; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Voices in the Labyrinth: Dialogues Around the Study of Nature, Feb. 1974; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
    -See also Ser.I, Seabury Press, Inc.
    -See also Oversized, Doubleday and Company, Inc.
  - Vorwort Zu Einer Grammatik der Biologie. Hundert Jahre Nukleinsäureforschung, [1970]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - What Really is DNA? Remarks on the Changing Aspects of a Scientific Concept, [1968]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
    - Folder 1, [1968] (Box 102)
    - Folder 2, [1968] (Box 102)
  - Zur Chemie der Bakterien. 1. Mitteilung: Über die Lipoide der Diphtheriebakterien. 2. Mitteilung: Über die Lipoidverteilung in Säurefesten Bakterien, [1931]; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
  - Zur Chemie der Diphtheriebakterien und Anderer Pathogener Mikroorganismen, 28 Sep. 1932; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 102)
- Series IIIa. Works by Chargaff, 1923-2002; 5 boxes: 2 linear feet
  Typewritten and handwritten outlines and drafts, primarily for non-scientific works written by Chargaff during the last two decades of his life. This series is arranged alphabetically by work. Some unpublished works are included, including poetry and other essays from the 1920s. In addition, this series includes a partial card file for his bibliography (see Series III) as well as his annual datebooks from 1929-1999. Most of this series is in German.
  - Against Patentomania, 1995; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Altwerden in Amerika, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Anzeige eines kleinen Kummers, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Aufschrei, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Aufschrei des Einzelnen, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Aufschrei eines Laien, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Baffled Methuselah, 1995; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Betrachtungen uber Desoxyribonukleinsaure als Shablone oder Text, 1968; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Bibliography, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Book Review - Mr. Rifkin, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Datebook: Papers from 1925 datebook, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Datebook: Papers from 1926 datebook, Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Der Kampf des Schriftstellers Karl Kraus fuer geistige Reinheit, 1928; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Die Flucht, 1973-74; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Die Wanderlang, 1927-1935; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Early Evening in Leternell, 1992; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Eine Zwei, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Einige Worte uber den Begriff "Essay", 2000; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Fallend ans des Welt - Uber die Schande, alt zu werden, 1997; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Few Unscientific Thoughts, A, 1989; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Im Wind du Welt, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - In Dispraise of Reductionism, 1996; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Inhalt, 1998; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Kann man die Seele klonieren?, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Liebe Freunde und Feinde, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Molecular Slavery, 2000; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notebook, 1918; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notebook: Logik Psychologie, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notebook: Papers from 1918 Notebook, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notebook: Papers from Logik Psychologie, undated, 1922, 1924; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notebook: Unbound pages, 1920; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notes, Poetry and Other Writings, 1919-1925; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notes, Poetry and other Writings, 1922-1929; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Notes, Poetry and other Writings, 1927-1935; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 122)
  - Poetry, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Selbstbesichtigung, 1998; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Stimmen im Labyrinth, 2000; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Uber Jonathan Swift (1), 1996; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Uber Jonathan Swift (2), 1996; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Unidentified Notes, 1976-2003; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Unidentified Notes, 1978-1986; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Viel Larm um wenig, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Wahrheit und Phantasie, 1998; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Wohin ist alles Verblasen?, 1997; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 123)
  - Bibliography Card File, 1923-2002; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 124)
  - Notebook: small looseleaf notebook, 1986-2000; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 125)
  - Notebook: small spiral bound notebook, 1999-2000; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 125)
  - Notebook: small looseleaf notebook, 1993; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 125)
  - Notebook: spiral bound notebook, undated; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 125)
  - Date book Japan Trip, 1958; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 126)
  - Datebooks: small date books, 1923, 1924-25, 1929, 1934(?), 1938-1993, 1995-1997; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 126)
  - Music Score from Logik Notebook, Undated (Box 155 (OVERSIZED))
- Series IIIb. Works by Chargaff: Reprints, 1977-1999; 2 boxes: .5 linear feet
  Reprints of Chargaff's writings. This series includes Chargaff's collection of his reprints arranged in his bibliographic order and numbered in his handwriting (see Series III and IIIa.) The American Philosophical Society has numbers 1-321 of Chargaff's collection of his reprints in the library of the APS and numbers 322-459 are filed here under "Bibliographic Numbers" in numerical order. The rest of this series is arranged alphabetically by title. Copies of reprints for articles that were missing in the original APS library collection (numbers 1-322) that were deposited with the 2002 deposit have been removed from this series to the APS library. Some of this series is in German.
  - Bibliography Numbers 322-340B, 1977-1980; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Bibliography Numbers 341-369, 1980-1982; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Bibliography Numbers 370-396A, 1983-1988; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Bibliography Numbers 419-453A, 1989-1991; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Bibliography Numbers 456-459, 1992-1997; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Buechersammlung, 1999; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Heraclitan Fire - excerpt, 1989; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Slap at the Bishops of Asilomar, A, 1975; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Vera Storia della Doppia Elicia, La, 1985; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
  - Was ist Natur?, unknown; Chargaff, Erwin (Box 127)
- Series IV. Works by others, 1929-1989; 15.5 linear feet
  Articles, notes, and papers written by colleagues and students of Chargaff. This series is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title. Authors with three or more manuscripts in this series include Waldo E. Cohn, David Elson, John N. Hawthorne, and John D. Karkas. Any works that Chargaff co-wrote with students and colleagues are filed in Series III alphabetically by title. Cross references are given for photographs which appear in this series.
  - Creativity and Merit in Art and Science, [1985]; Alfert, Max (Box 103)
  - A Modest Disposal of History, [1985]; Alfert, Max (Box 103)
  - Ribonucleoprotein of Calf Liver, 1956; Aminoff, David (Box 103)
  - Some Comments on Science, Industry, and the Academic Life--Address, 28 Oct. 1961; Beadle, George W. (Box 103)
  - Drastic Alteration of Ribosomal RNA-s and Ribosomal Proteins in Showdomycin Resistant E. Coli, [1970]; Beljanski, Mirko, Pierre Bourgarel, and Monique Beljanski (Box 103)
  - Colchicine Experiments, 5 Jun. 1956; Benitez, Helena H. (Box 103)
  - Response of Cells in Vitro to Various Cellular Preparations, [195-?]; Benitez, Helena H. (Box 103)
  - Identification of Individual Components in Each Fraction, 1965; Black, Donald N. (Box 103)
  - Synthesis of Ribonucleic Acids in the Adrenal Cortex: Early Effects of Adreno-Corticotropic Hormone on Specific RNA Fractions, Jul. 1965; Bransome, Edwin D., Jr. (Box 104)
  - Studies on Enzymes Involved in Nucleic Acid Metabolism, 1953; Brawerman, George (Box 104)
  - Heterogeneity of Deoxyribonucleic Acids, [1953]; Brown, Geoffrey L. and N. Watson (Box 104)
  - Nucleic Acid Metabolism in Relation to the Production of Formed Elements of Blood, n.d.; Brown, George (Box 104)
  - Variation of the Molar Extinction Coefficient of Native Deoxyribonucleic Acid with Base Composition, 1962; Bunch, Stuart L. (Box 104)
  - Digestion of Poly AC with Ribonuclease, 28 Jan. 1969; Cassuto, Era (Box 104)
  - The Phospholipids in the Thrombo-plastic Protein from Lungs, [194-]; Cohen, Seymour S., (Seymour Stanley), 1917- (Box 104)
  - Report on Research, 27 Jun. 1937; Cohen, Seymour S., (Seymour Stanley), 1917- (Box 104)
  - Desalting of Nucleotides by Gel Filtration, [1965]; Cohn, Waldo E. and Mayo Uziel (Box 104)
  - 5-Ribosyl Uracil, a Carbon-carbon Ribofuranosyl Nucleoside in Ribonucleic Acids, [1958]; Cohn, Waldo E. (Box 104)
  - Identification of the Purine Nucleotides a and b as the 2' and 3' Phospho-ribosides, Respectively, 1954; Cohn, Waldo E. and Joseph X. Khym (Box 104)
  - Ribose Phosphates: Production from Nucleotides, Ion-Exchange Separation, and Characterization, 1954; Cohn, Waldo E. and J.X. Khym, and D.G Doherty (Box 104)
  - Further Molecular Weight and Size Studies of Desoxypentose Nucleic Acid, [1953]; Doty, Paul, M.E. Reichmann, S.A. Rice, and C.A. Thomas III (Box 104)
  - Preparation of Sodium Desoxyribonucleate, [195-]; Dounce, Alexander L., Norman S. Simmons, and Ernest R.M. Kay (Box 104)
  - The Preparation of Sodium Ribonucleate with the Use of Sodium Dodecyl Sulfate, [1953]; Dounce, Alexander L. and Ernest R.M. Kay (Box 104)
  - Costs and Benefits of Recombinant DNA, Jun. 1976; Dyson, Freeman J. (Box 104)
  - Synthèse de la L-uridine 5' Triphosphate, 1972; Ellouz, Radhouane (Box 104)
  - A Critique of Reductionism, [1976]; Elsasser, Walter M., 1904-1991 (Box 104)
  - Escherichia Coli Experiments--Notes, 1954-1955; Elson, David (Box 104)
  - Latent Enzymatic Activity of a Ribonucleoprotein Isolated from Escherichia Coli, [195-]; Elson, David (Box 104)
  - Notes, n.d.; Elson, David (Box 104)
  - On the Desoxyribonucleic Acid Content of Sea Urchin Gametes, [195-]; Elson, David (Box 104)
  - Preparation and Properties of a Ribonucleoprotein Isolated from Escherichia Coli, [195-]; Elson, David (Box 104)
  - Ribonucleoprotein Experiments, 1955; Elson, David (Box 104)
  - Table of PNA Analyses, [195-]; Elson, David (Box 104)
  - The Nomenclature of Cyclohexitols and Their Derivatives, [1950]; Fletcher, Hewitt G., Jr. and Laurens Anderson, and Henry A. Lardy (Box 104)
  - Notes, 1950; Folch-Pi, Jordi (Box 104)
  - Sur l'inhibition par l'Actinomycine de l'Initiation de la Synthèse de RNA in Vitro, [1966]; Fromageot, Pierre, A. Sentenac, and A. Ruet (Box 104)
  - Protein Synthesis by DNA-Molecules, [1954]; Gamow, George and C.G.H. Tompkins (Box 104)
  - Results of Nucleic Acid Analysis from Chicken Erythrocytes, 1953; Gandelman, Bertha (Box 104)
  - 'Clonal Selection and After,' and After, 1979; Gershon, Richard K. (Box 104)
  - Comments on Sonnenborn's Letter, n.d.; Goodman, Fred (Box 104)
  - Inositol Experiments, 1951-1952; Hawthorne, John N. (Box 104)
  - Membrane Phospholipids, Exocytosis and Cell Division, 1979; Hawthorne, John N., Norazila Mohd, Adnan Lymberopoulos, and George Lymberopoulos (Box 104)
  - Phosphoinositides, [1959]; Hawthorne, John Nigel (Box 104)
  - On the Nature of Macromolecular Coding in Neuronal Memory, [1963]; Hechter, Oscar and Ian D.K. Halkerston (Box 104)
  - Reversal of Chloramphenicol Action by Sphingosine, 1961; Horowitz, Jack (Box 104)
  - The Mononucleotide Content of Some Desoxyribose Nucleic Acids, [195-]; Hurst, R.O., A.M. Marko, and G.C. Butler (Box 104)
  - Preparations of RNA from Pancreas, n.d.; Johnson, Edward A. (Box 104)
  - Here Comes Everybody by William C. Schutz--Review, 4 Jul. 1971; Kaplan, Donald (Box 104)
  - Coupling of Replication to Transcription in Vitro, 1972; Karkas, John D. (Box 105)
  - A New Method of Assay for Polynucleotide Ligase, [1973]; Karkas, John D. (Box 105)
  - Summary of 2 Hr. Formic Acid Hydrolysis I of NH4 Uridylate, 5 Jan. 1949; Karkas, John D. (Box 105)
  - Proteins, 3 Feb. 1967; Koshland, Daniel E., Jr. (Box 105)
  - Enzymatic Deamination of Al Serine, 1948; Kream, Jacob (Box 105)
  - On the Cytosine Deaminase of Yeast, [195-]; Kream, Jacob (Box 105)
  - Neueus zur Erfassung und Vermeidung der Postoperativen Fernthrombose, 23 Jan. 1936; Lenggenhager, [?] (Box 105)
  - Free Ribonucleic Acid Particles in Homogenates of Plant Tissue, [1955]; Lindner, R.C., Hugh C. Kirkpatrick, and T.E. Weeks (Box 105)
  - Notes, n.d.; Lipshitz, Rakoma (Box 105)
  - Constructing a Human Tumor Virus?, Jul. 1976; Loeb, Lawrence A. and Kenneth D. Tartof (Box 105)
  - Machines and Vitalists: Reflections on the Ideology of Cybernetics, [1965]; McClintock, Robert O. (Box 105)
  - Notes, n.d.; Magasanik, Boris (Box 105)
  - Studies in the Sphingo-Lipids Series. XXI. C20-Sphingosine, a New Long-Chain Base of Animal Origin, 1961; Majhofer-Orescanin, B. and M. Prostenik (Box 105)
  - Asymmetric Transcription of B. Subtilis E. Coli and S. Typhimurium DNA for Ribosomal and Transfer RNA, Margulies, Lola, Virgilija Remeza, and Rivka Rudner (Box 105)
  - Distribution of Guanylic Acid in RNA of Yeast and Tobacco Mosaic Virus, [1960]; Miura, Kinichiro (Box 105)
  - Experiments of Alkali Stable Dinucleosides of E. Coli s-RNA, 1968; Morisawa, Seiji (Box 105)
  - Frankenstein and Recombinant DNA, Jan. 1979; Morowitz, Harold J. (Box 105)
  - On the Mechanism of the Methylation of the 2'-OH Group in Ribose of SRNA in E. Coli, 1966; Mukherjee, Amal Kumar (Box 105)
  - An Investigation of the Properties of MAK Chromatography of Denatured Deoxyribonucleic Acids, 23 Jun. 1971; Nielsen, Jennifer Bronwen Kahn (Box 105)
  - Rates of Expression of Markers on Separated Strands in B. Subtilis Transformation, 16 Jun. 1971; Nielsen, Jennifer Bronwen Kahn (Box 105)
  - Isolation of Carrot Protein, [194-]; Nyman, Melvin A. (Box 105)
  - Heparin Use at Presbyterian Hospital, 28 Oct. 1938; Olson, Kenneth B. (Box 105)
  - How Should Recombinant DNA Research Be Controlled?, 1976; Pollack, Robert (Box 105)
  - Heparin, 8 Nov. 1937; Reinert, M. (Box 105)
  - Alternative Codes and Templates, [1962]; Roberts, Richard B. (Box 105)
  - Heraclitean Fire by Erwin Chargaff--Review, 1984; Rota, Gian-Carlo, 1932-1999 (Box 105)
  - The Analysis of Purine Sequences in DNA, 1962-1963; Rüst, Peter (Box 105)
  - Attempts to Measure DNA Strand Separation by Partial Deamination, 1962; Rüst, Peter (Box 105)
  - Blood Clotting Experiments, 1945-1946; Saidel, Helen (Box 105)
  - Spectrophotometric Assay, [1951-?]; Schmidt, Gerhard (Box 105)
  - Degradation of Ribonucleic Acid in Escherichia Coli in Phosphorus-Deficient Culture, n.d.; Shigeura, Harold T. (Box 105)
  - Ultra-Centrifuge Procedure, 1955; Siegel, Bernard (Box 105)
  - The Dawn of Genetic Engineering, 16 Jul. 1975; Sinsheimer, Robert L. (Box 105)
  - Is the Nucleic Acid Message in a Two-Symbol Code?, [1959]; Sinsheimer, Robert L. (Box 105)
  - Alternative Therapies, edited by G.T. Lewith--Review, [1985]; Skrabanek, Petr (Box 105)
  - In Defence of Destructive Criticism, [1985]; Skrabanek, Petr (Box 105)
  - Nomenclature of the Long-Chain Bases Isolated from Lipids, n.d.; Stanacev, Nikola Z. and Herbert E. Carter (Box 105)
  - Calf Thymus Isoenzymes of Ribonuclease H. Purification and Properties, [1977]; Stavrianopoulos, Yiannis G. (Box 105)
  - The Concept of Disease and the Birth of Modern Medicine, [1982]; Tavassoli, Mehdi (Box 105)
  - Barium Glycerophosphate Experiments, 1946; Unidentified (Box 105)
  - DNA-Polylysine and DNA-Polyvinylamine Complexes, Unidentified (Box 105)
  - Heparin Experiments, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 105)
  - The Isolation of Highly Polymerized Human Desoxypentose Nucleic Acid from Sperm, Unidentified (Box 105)
  - Isolation of Spinach Protein, [194-]; Unidentified (Box 105)
  - Leucocyte Experiments, 1943; Unidentified (Box 105)
  - Notes, 1948-1955, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 106)
  - Periodate Oxidation of Inositol, 1946; Unidentified (Box 106)
  - Periodate Oxidation of Mannitol, 1946; Unidentified (Box 106)
  - Phosphorus Analyses of Staphlococci, 1946; Unidentified (Box 106)
  - Tobacco Mosaic Virus, 1950; Unidentified (Box 106)
  - Unterchungen über Choleïnsäuren mit Fettsäuren mit Verzweigten Kohlenstoffketten als Koordinationszentrum, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 106)
  - Warburg Experiments, [194-]; Unidentified (Box 106)
  - Genetic Recombination: The Technological Redesign of Living Organisms, [1976]; Wald, George (Box 106)
  - A Glucosamine-Muramic-Adenylic-Amino Acid Complex from Bacterial Cells, [1961]; Watson, R.W. and K.E. Cooksey, C. Roy, and R.A. Anwar (Box 106)
  - The Federal Laboratories and Science Education in the Age of Big Science, 27 Nov. 1961; Weinberg, Alvin Martin, 1915-2006 (Box 106)
  - Action of X-Rays on Nucleic Acids, [1949]; Weiss, Joseph J. (Box 106)
  - When Does Information Become Knowledge?, 14 Jan. 1972; Wyatt, H.V. (Box 106)
  - Evidence for a Repeating Unit in Plant Virus Nucleic Acids, [1954]; Ycas, Martynas (Box 106)
  - Depolymerase Experiments, 1947; Zamenhof, Stephan (Box 106)
  - Notes, n.d.; Zamenhof, Stephan (Box 106)
- Series IVa. Works by Others, 1976-2002; 1 box: .5 linear feet
  Articles, drawings, and essays by correspondents and acquaintances of Chargaff during his later years. This series is arranged alphabetically by author. Some of this series is in German.
  - Deitrich, Wolfgang, undated (Box 128)
  - Dex, Norbert, 1998 (Box 128)
  - Durand, Pierre, undated (Box 128)
  - Forsdyke, Donald R., 2000; Mortimer, James R. (Box 128)
  - Hargittai, Istvan, 1988-1989; Hargittai, István (Box 128)
  - Heeger, Hellmut, 1998-1999 (Box 128)
  - Hugenschmidt-Thurkauf, Inge M., undated; Inge M. Hugenschmidt-Thurkauf (Box 128)
  - Kobler, Michael, 1995-1998 (Box 128)
  - Kreiger, Hans, 2000, 2002 (Box 128)
  - Leistikow, K. U., 1999 (Box 128)
  - Lessing, Kolja, 2001-2002 (Box 128)
  - Mei del Testa, Alberto, 1993 (Box 128)
  - Meider, Wolfgang, 1998 (Box 128)
  - Miscellaneous Authors, 1976, 1998, 2000-2001 (Box 128)
  - Pieper, Franz, 1999 (Box 128)
  - Reitmeier, Henner, 2000 (Box 128)
  - Schwilk, Heimo, undated (Box 128)
  - Szanto, Tibor, 1986 (Box 128)
  - Tesche, Holger, 1995, 1996; Teschke, Holger, 1958- (Box 128)
  - Unkown authors, 1997, undated (Box 128)
  - Welzig, Werner, 1996; Welzig, werner (Box 128)
  - Wills, Peter, 1999 (Box 128)
- Series V. Research notes, 1929-1951; 2.25 linear feet